Gautier MECHLING

(+86) 158 20 40 46 21 nilhcem@gmail.com French, 26 years old

Java / JavaEE Developer

Profile

Over three years experience in designing and developing client and server-side applications.

Excellent analytical, design and problem-solving abilities.

Highly motivated and committed to delivering the highest standard of work.

Technical skills

Languages: Java, C/C++, C#

Frameworks: Java EE (Servlets, JSP), Hibernate, Spring (aop - mvc - dao - orm - security)

Scripting languages: Javascript (Prototype / jQuery), Groovy, Shell, Perl, PHP, VBA

Web: HTML, XML, CSS (Blueprint, Less), JSTL

Methodologies: OOAD, UML, Design Patterns, Relational Database Design Java Tools/APIs: Ant, Maven, Velocity, Quartz, SLF4J, Swing, JUnit, Sitemesh

Quality / CI: Findbugs, PMD, Checkstyle, Sonar, Hudson/Jenkins

Other: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SVN, Git, HTTPd, Tomcat, JBoss, Eclipse, Emacs, SDL, Qt

OS: Windows, GNU/Linux, Mac OS X

Professional experience

Software engineer (Java / Java EE), AsiaInspection (Shenzhen, China)

September 2009 - present (2+ years)

- Taking over unfinished projects from subcontractors, making them stable and functional, boosting them respecting deadlines.
- Main developer of two successfully launched services (AsiaCalculator.com Asialnquiry.com) to simplify costs calculation and products imports from Asia to Western countries.
- Improving current processes by implementing and maintaining test and production environments (RedHat), internal revision control system (SVN over SSH) and dependencies repository (Maven Nexus).
- Participating in the conception and implementation of the company's new technical project (based on Logback, Maven, Spring, Hibernate and Axis), to provide web-services for the current business application (in Lotus Script / Java).
- Helping junior developers (Asian and Westerners) under my responsibility, and bringing fresh ideas to other project leaders.

Software analyst (Java / Java EE), Sopra Group (Montreuil, France)

March 2009 - August 2009 (6 months)

In charge of studying and implementing security and identity management softwares:

- Single Sign On and Federated Identity software analysis.
- Finding and fixing security flaws on French government websites powered by Lutece Portal Engine.

Software engineer (C / C++), Mindscape (Rueil-Malmaison, France)

September 2008 - February 2009 (6 months)

Nintendo DS software/tool development (C / C++ / Perl):

- 2 commercial products launched in Europe with tight milestones and deadlines.
- Closely working with internal & external development and QA teams.
- Improving development tool chain.

Education and diplomas

2006 – 2009 Master's Degree in Computer Science (with honors. GPA 3.52)

EPITECH - European Institute of Technology (Paris, France)

2004 – 2006 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

CNAM - Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers (Paris, France)

Hobbies, interests and values

Communication: English (fluent) - French (native speaker) - Chinese (basic knowledge).

Programming: Developing cross-platform and free softwares for PC and handheld devices in my spare time.

Learning/Travels: One year study in Dalian Polytechnic University (China).

Helping/Sharing: Active contributor to open source projects, such as Prestashop (eCommerce shopping cart software).